# Danil Syah Arihardjo

Sumedang, West Java, Indonesia

# **Summary**

Hi, you can call me Danil. I am a computer graduate from an information systems study program at one of the universities in Indonesia.

I have more than 5 years of working experience in a private telecommunications company in Indonesia as an internet network technician. My job duties and responsibilities are ensuring stability and monitoring the internet connection, as well as finding solutions to customer complaints.

I am a tech enthusiast. I am able to work independently or in a team, by working together we can share opinions and solutions to make work easier.

Besides being busy with work routines, I also take the time to learn programming languages, to see what I've learned you can visit my Github at https://github.com/danilsyah

# **Experience**



## Area Coordinator

PT. Batam Bintan Telekomunikasi

Aug 2014 - Jan 2022 (7 years 6 months)

Tugas dan tanggung jawab pekerjaan memastikan stabilitas dan memantau koneksi internet, menjaga perangkat jaringan selalu terhubung, serta mencari solusi atas keluhan pelanggan serta berkoordinasi dengan divisi Lain.



#### HaykalWifi RT/RW Net

Jan 2021 - Dec 2021 (1 year)

Membangun Usaha Jaringan RT/RW Net Menggunakan Router Mikrotik dan Access Point untuk memperluas Signal Jaringan WiFi

# IT Support Freelance

PT. Buana Mega Wisatama

Aug 2021 - Oct 2021 (3 months)

Membangun Jaringan Interkoneksi Local Menggunakan Router Mikrotik dengan menggunakan Fitur Hotspot. dan alokasi management bandwidth menggunakan metode brust time limit untuk kebutuhan Office PT. Buana Mega Wisatama

## **Education**



## STTI Tanjungpinang

Bachelor's degree, Information Technology

# SMK Negeri 4 Bandung

Rekayasa Perangkat Lunak Program 4 Tahun 2009 - 2013

## **Licenses & Certifications**

MikroTik Certified Network Associate - PT. Inixindo Persada Rekayasa Komputer Issued Oct 2017 - Expires Oct 2020 1710NA3246

MikroTik Certified Routing Engineer - PT. Rainusa Indonesia (Rainusa Training Batam)

Issued Feb 2020 - Expires Feb 2023 2002RE1031

- Full Stack Website Developer Laravel Framework BuildWith Angga dxZHOabhxp
- Belajar Membuat Aplikasi Back-End untuk Pemula Dicoding Indonesia
  Issued May 2021 Expires May 2024
  0LZ0D0L0NX65
- Belajar Dasar Pemrograman JavaScript Dicoding Indonesia
  Issued Apr 2021 Expires Apr 2024
  L4PQMJR02ZO1
- Belajar Dasar Git dengan GitHub Dicoding Indonesia
  Issued Aug 2021 Expires Aug 2024
  98XWKV539XM3
- **Belajar MongoDB untuk Pemula** CodePolitan 5R72HVN
- Workshop Career to the Moon for Software Engineer Novice Alterra Academy 039/SER/CTTM/X/2021
- Cloud Practitioner Essentials (Belajar Dasar AWS Cloud) Dicoding Indonesia
  Issued Oct 2021 Expires Oct 2024
  1OP8LJK1LZQK
- MoSQL Database with MongoDB Digital Talent Scholarship

- Learn Python : From Basics to Data Structure Udemy
- Algoritma dan Pemrograman Dasar CodePolitan AC61XKW
- Jaringan Komputer Dasar ID-Networkers (IDN.ID)
- Cisco Dasar ID-Networkers (IDN.ID)

# **Skills**

REST APIs • MySQL • GitHub • Mikrotik • LAN Switching • Routing • MongoDB • Python (Programming Language)